taxbrain.com 2004-06-03

# TaxBrain: Complete Privacy Policy

**Petz Enterprises, Incorporated (PEI) takes privacy seriously.** We process millions of financial transactions each year and have implemented a variety of technologies and policies to protect privacy. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

As an Authorized IRS e-file provider our company adheres to Federal and state regulations designed to ensure the security and confidentiality of personal information shared with our company. TaxBrain exceeds the federal requirements and meets or exceeds our industry standards for security and privacy. 

Petz Enterprises, Inc. has created a web-based tax product designed to quickly and easily fulfill tax compliance requirements in the United States. We have developed this application using the most sophisticated encryption technology on the market. Security is our top priority and protecting privacy is what you should expect from PEI. 

Because of the financial nature of our business, our Web sites are not designed to appeal to children under the age of 13. Therefore, we do not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive any information from children. Petz Enterprises, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site http://www.taxbrain.com/ (TaxBrain, TaxBrain.com). Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users' privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

Questions regarding the TaxBrain Web sites' privacy statement, our online privacy policy, our information practices or other aspects of privacy on our Web sites should be directed to us at [support@TaxBrain.com ](mailto:support@taxbrain.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the [TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process ](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.php). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve users concerns. 

  * What personally identifiable information TaxBrain collects.
  * What organization collects the information.
  * How TaxBrain uses the information.
  * With whom TaxBrain may share user information.
  * What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
  * What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under TaxBrain control.
  * How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

Below is detailed information on how users can correct any inaccuracies in the information

Privacy Policy Effective Date: May 10, 2004

| Information Collection and Use  
---  
  
**Information Collection**

Petz Enterprises, Inc. is the sole owner of the information collected on TaxBrain.com. TaxBrain collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

Back to Top

**Registration**

In order to use this Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information such as name, address, phone number and email address. We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which they have expressed interest.

**Order Information**

We request information from users on our order form. A user must provide contact information such as name, email, address and phone number and financial information such as credit card number, expiration date and bank account information. All financial information collected on our site will remain absolutely confidential and will never be disclosed to any non-affiliated companies except as required by law. Financial information includes information such as credit card numbers and bank account information. We may store such information on our secure servers to expedite processing of certain services and products we provide to you. We may use your contact information to notify you of important product updates, significant tax law changes or promotional opportunities – if you have chosen to receive such offers. 

**Tax Related Information**

When a tax return is prepared on TaxBrain the information contained in the tax return will be treated with extreme care and confidence. As a method for detecting fraud in tax information transmitted via the Internet, the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) requires Petz Enterprises to provide to the IRS, in connection with the electronic filing of tax returns, the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer from which the return originated. We are also required to notify the IRS whether the e-mail address of the person electronically filing the return has been collected. 

**Tax Estimator and W-4 Calculator**

Information entered into the Tax Estimator and W-4 Calculator is used solely to provide tax estimates and does not collect personally identifiable information. The information that you provide is not saved or transferred to any other party. 

Back to Top

**Identifying and Contact Information**

From time to time, users may be asked to provide certain Identifying and Contact Information, such as name, e-mail address, mailing address, telephone number, user name, and demographic information. This information is used to verify identity, determine eligibility for special programs or services we may offer and complete transactions. At times it will be necessary to use Contact Information to communicate with users concerning administrative matters, responding to user requests and notifying users of the status of their transactions. However, we will not disclose Identifying and Contact Information to third parties without prior consent, except as required by law.

**Contest/Promotions and Surveys**

At times we will administer contests and online surveys where we will ask for contact information, such as e-mail address and demographic information, such as zip code, age or income level. The reason the information is being collected will be disclosed with the contest or survey at the time the information is collected.

**Public Forums**

This site may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available. Information disclosed in these areas becomes public information. Caution should be exercised when disclosing personal information in these applications.

**Cookies**

A "cookie" is a small piece of information that our Web sites may provide to a user's browser while they are at our site. Registered users on TaxBrain will receive a cookie when they login. This cookie is maintained by their browser and contains their unique identifier. This cookie is also used to authenticate their identity and provide access to areas of our Web site that are limited to registered users, such as those for tax return preparation and electronic filing. The cookie is tied to the user's account id. Only TaxBrain knows what personal information matches the account id number. There is no way any personally identifiable information could be directly extracted from our cookie. However, if a user has opted to have their username and password remembered, the information is stored in the cookie.

We also contract with Coremetrics, a service provider, to provide us with a data collection and reporting service. This service allows us to better provide our product and services to you. Coremetrics’ only role is to help us conduct our business and deliver the most  
relevant products and services. Coremetrics is contractually restricted from using your information in any other manner. If you would like to deactivate our ability to analyze your  
anonymous browsing and purchase behavior through the use of this service, or find out more  
about our service provider, including its privacy policy and how to opt out, go to:  
<http://www.coremetrics.com/info_eluminate2.html>.

Back to Top

**Log Files**

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. With or without cookies, our Web site keeps track of usage data, such as internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. We use this data to better understand Web site usage in the aggregate so that we know what areas of our Web site users prefer. This information is stored in log files and is used for aggregated and statistical reporting.   

Third Party Intermediaries  
  
We use an outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Financial Service Providers**

We partner with other third party banks, such as the Santa Barbara Bank & Trust, to provide specific financial services. When users sign up for these particular services, we share names, or other contact information (such as name, address, social security number and phone number) that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

Back to Top

**  
Business Transitions **

In the event TaxBrain goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via email and prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.  

**Links**

This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Petz Enterprises Inc., are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.  

**Surveys& Contests **

From time to time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users' personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice or they are under contract with us. For instance, we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, but they may not use users' personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

Back to Top  

Communications from the Site  
  
**Special Offers and Updates**

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify registration. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter.

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we also provide a self-service opt-out of these communications at <http://www.taxbrain.com/optout.asp>.   

**  
Service Announcements **

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.  

**  
Customer Service **

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the your wishes.

Our site does link to other sites in order to provide all of the tax and financial services users might need. PEI has partnered with these sites for content use and may share user information disclosed on our site with them on an aggregate basis for advertisement tracking only. We will never disclose personally Identifying information without prior consent. TaxBrain provides services in conjunction with third party companies. With your permission, your TaxBrain account will have the ability to log into accounts, and upload information to your TaxBrain account, that you hold with third party partners. This upload of information to TaxBrain.com is done to fulfill the full service of our site and no other purpose. For example, we can upload W-2s from employers and other content for forms from our partner organizations. 

These are the instances in which we will share users' personal information.

Back to Top  

Security Information  
  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. 

TaxBrain account information is password-protected so that only the registered owner of an account will have access to their personal information. Account information may be updated by entering a user name and password to gain access to the account. We strongly recommend that users do not share their user name and password with anyone. PEI will never ask a user for their user name or password via unsolicited phone call or e-mail. Security is of utmost importance to Petz Enterprises and we use the latest SSL technology to protect confidential information.  

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected computers. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users' information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, behind a locked door in a locked facility. If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to [support@taxbrain.com ](mailto:support@taxbrain.com).  

**  
Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information **

We provide the opportunity to update or correct the contact and tax return information provided to us. The tax return information and personally identifiable information collected through this site is contained in tax returns and in product registration information. Once a tax return has been completed using the TaxBrain Web product, and directed that it be electronically filed, it cannot be changed because the tax return has become a legal record of the tax filing. Any changes made to a tax return after it has already been electronically filed, and acknowledged by the IRS, will generate a Form 1040X (amended return).  

**  
Notification of Changes **

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner.  

Contact Us  
  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

> Postal Address:  
>  PO Box 611  
>  Tracy, CA 95378
> 
> Phone: 866.829.2724  
>  Fax: 209.835.0409  
>  Email: [support@taxbrain.com](mailto:support@taxbrain.com)
> 
> Web site URL: http://www.taxbrain.com

PRIVATE WEB FORM EMAIL  
Your most secure means of support is the personal web form provided within your myTaxBrain page. From there we can answer tax, technical, customer service and other support questions.

All questions receive a response within 24 hours, while most questions are answered right away.  

Back to Top

>
